"Third Training Grounds"
（ナルト）いくぜ
Let's go!
Shadow Clone Jutsu.
影分身かげぶんしんの術
Not bad.
（はたけカカシ）やるなあ
Nice... Since he's trapped in midair...
（春野はるのサクラ）うまい！
身動きの取れない
空中での移動手段に
he used the Shadow Clone Jutsu
as a means for movement.
影分身を利用した
Transform!
（ナルト）んぐっ
ううっ
うっ…
Okay, that's as far as you go.
（カカシ）はい そこまで
（カカシ）身長 だいぶ伸びたな
He's gotten pretty tall.
And not only that...
おまけに…
（ナルト）フッ ヘヘ…
His timing for using
the Shadow Clone Jutsu has gotten better.
（カカシ）影分身の使い方
タイミング うまくなっちゃって
Oho...
（自来也じらいや）ほお～
Not bad.
（綱手つなで）やるなあ
That's incredible.
（シズネ）すごい
（カカシ）成長したな ナルト
You've grown, haven't you, Naruto?
However...
だが…
Well, it seems you're just
as impatient as ever.
まっ せっかちなのは
相変わらず
変わってないみたいだな
I haven't even said start yet,
have I?
まだスタートは言ってないだろ？
（カカシ）そう慌てんなよ
Don't be so hasty.
I haven't even said start yet, have I?
まだ スタートとは言ってないだろ？
Now then, let's begin.
じゃあ 始めるぞ
Ready... start!
（カカシ）よ～い
スタート
（サクラ）あっ
（ナルト）うっ
♪～
A voice heard in the distance gives me a hint.
tooku de kikoeru koe wo hinto ni
One by one like-minded people are standing up.
hitori mata hitori tachiagaru doushi
Lets overturn all the everyday, monotonous things.
kurikaesu dake no fudan doori kutsugaesu
I'm ready, are you ready?
junbi iize are you ready
A shiver spreads through my body, violently ringing stomping.
karadajuu furuwasu shindou ni hageshiku uchinarase yo stomping
Constantly stirring in me, it calls me.
taezu tsuki ugokasu call me
Catching that unchanging, never wavering story, Come on!
kawarazu yuru ga nutsukamu story come on
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Are you ready for a few risks?
hey yo whoa tashou no risuku wa kakugo desho
You have to get up no matter how many times you fall. (Get it on!)
nanka korundatte tatsu get it on
It's not some conspiracy, just a paper-thin session
nare ai ja nai ze kami hitoe no sesshon
The pent up feelings turn into a crystal.
irikunda kanjou kidzukiageta kesshou
The rising cheers will become your courage.
wakiagaru kansei ga yuuki tonaru
So stand up now, no matter how much pain you feel.
tachiagareba ima ijou kurushimi tomonau
But in the end I'm sure you'll laugh.
soredemo saigo wa kitto warau
Everything will be swept away in victory and cheer.
subete sarau shouri to kansei
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
～♪
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
（カカシ）じゃあ 始めるぞ
Now then, let's begin!
よ～い
Ready... start!
スタート
（サクラ）あっ
（ナルト）うっ
クソ～
Damn it!
I've been had!
やられたってばよ
（サクラ）もう～ ナルトのドジ！
Come on, Naruto, you goof!
The Results
of Training
（サソリ）ご苦労
Good work...
Do you remember me?
俺のこと思い出してくれた？
（由良ゆうら）あ…
もちろんです サソリ様
Of course, I do, Sasori-sama.
（デイダラ）そりゃ そうだ
Of course, he does.
忘れてたら
術になんねえだろ？ うん
It wouldn't be much of
a Jutsu if he didn't.
（サソリ）記憶が戻れば
忠実な部下だぜ
They become loyal subordinates
after regaining their memory.
（デイダラ）そろそろ いいか？
I say it's about ready?
よし できたぞ うん
All right, it's done...
（デイダラ）サソリの旦那は
ここで見てればいい うん
Sasori, my man.
You watch from here...
Okay.
里へは…
I'll attack the village...
from above.
上から攻める
どうだい 旦那
この芸術的造形は？ うん
What do you think of
this artistic form...?
（サソリ）あんまり
待たせんなよ デイダラ
Don't make me wait too long, Deidara!
（デイダラ）ヘッ…
（デイダラ）一尾(いちび) 守鶴(しゅかく)の人柱力(じんちゅうりき)
砂漠の我愛羅(があら)か うん
One-Tail, the Jinchuriki of Shukaku,
Gaara of the desert, eh?
さて どんなものか
Now then, I wonder what he's like.
（綱手）さあ どうする？ サクラ
Now...
What're you going to do, Sakura?
Right? Above? Left?
（サクラ）右
上
左
Behind?
後ろ
どこでもないなら…
If he's in none of those places...
（サクラ）下！
He must be below.
（ナルト）あ～ とっ とっ…
（ナルト）ええ…
Huh?
（カカシ）な…
なんつうバカ力だ
Wh-What ridiculous strength.
よし 上出来だ
All right, well done.
（カカシ）五代目～
Fifth...
You didn't just teach Sakura
Medical Ninjutsu, huh?
サクラに教えたの
医療忍術だけじゃないのね
（自来也）あのキレ具合と あの怪力
That short temper and
incredible strength.
見事な綱手２号を育てやがったのォ
She raised a splendid second Tsunade.
Kakashi-sensei.
（サクラ）カカシ先生
（カカシ）ん？
Huh?
見～つけた
I found you.
（ナルト）サ…
サクラちゃんの前でバカするの
I'd... I'd better stop acting like
an idiot in front of Sakura-chan.
もう やめよ
I'll get killed...!
殺される
（カカシ）最大チャクラを
一気に体内で練り上げ
She built up her maximum
Chakra inside her body at once
瞬時に拳に全集中
and instantly concentrated
all of it into her fist.
That's a feat that can't be done
without considerable Chakra control.
相当なチャクラコントロールが
なけりゃ できない芸当だ
医療忍術に怪力か
Medical Ninjutsu along
with superhuman strength...
いや それだけじゃない
No. It's more than that.
サクラは 本来
幻術げんじゅつタイプだからな
Sakura's originally a Genjutsu-type,
after all.
She might just become
a better Kunoichi than the Fifth.
こりゃ 五代目以上の
くノ一になるかもね
（カカシ）よ～し 今度は
俺のほうからもいきますか
All right, now I guess
it's my turn, huh?
One.
Two.
Three.
So there are three people
guarding the skies...
上空の見張りが３人か うん
しかし なかなか芸術的なデザイン
してやがんじゃねえか この里
Still, this village sure has
quite the artistic design to it.
まさに 壊しがいが
あるってもんだが うん
It's certainly worth destroying, though...
（デイダラ）ここは 隠密行動だな
It's time for covert action from here on.
（カカシ）いる いる
There he is.
忍たるもの 基本は
気配を消し隠れるべし
The basics for a Shinobi are
to eliminate their presence
and remain hidden.
This is totally different from
back then.
あのころとは大違いだな
（カカシ）忍たるもの 基本は
気配を消し隠れるべし
The basics for a Shinobi
are to eliminate their presence
and remain hidden.
All right, everyone seems
to be well hidden...
（カカシ）よ～し
みんな うまく隠れ…
（カカシ）ん？
あっ いざ 尋常に勝負 勝負～
Now, fight me fair and square!
Say, aren't you just a little bit off there?
（カカシ）あのさあ
お前 ちとズレてない？
（カカシ）おっと
（ナルト）うっ うわ～
（カカシ）２人とも 教えてやる
Let me teach the two of you something.
忍戦術しのびせんじゅつの心得 その１
Shinobi Battle Skills, part one... Taijutsu.
体術たいじゅつ
隙あり！
You're wide open!
If I can hit him once...
（サクラ）１発 当たれば
It won't mean a thing
if you don't hit me.
（カカシ）当たらなければ
どうということはない
（カカシ）おっ
Phew, that was a close one.
うへ～ 危ない 危ない
影分身の術
Shadow Clone Jutsu.
（カカシ）ん？
（ナルト）いくぞ
Here I come!
All right, bring it on.
（カカシ）よ～し こい！
もらった！
The bell's mine.
（カカシ）ぬわ～
（ナルト）うわっ
You won't get away!
逃がすか！
えっ？ 影舞葉かげぶよう
Dancing Leaf Shadow...?!
あっ
これってば ゲジマユの！
This is Bushy Brow's...!
カカシ先生のコピー忍術
It's Kakashi-sensei's Copy Ninjutsu!
（ナルト）うわっ うわあ～！
（カカシ）さあ 本体はどこだ？
Now... where's the real one?
（ナルト）ここだってばよ
Right here.
（カカシ）うっ
（ナルト）秘伝 体術奥義たいじゅつおうぎ
Secret Finger Jutsu.
（カカシ）ぬおっ おお…
（ナルト）千年殺せんねんごろし
A Thousand Years of Death!
（カカシ）どわ～
Now... where's the real one?
（カカシ）さあ 本体はどこだ？
（ナルト）ここだってばよ
Right here!
（カカシ）うっ
（ナルト）秘伝 体術奥義
Secret Finger Jutsu!
（カカシ）ぬおっ おお…
（ナルト）千年殺し
A Thousand Years of Death!
（カカシ）どわ～
（ナルト）うっ クソ～
外したってばよ
Damn it. I missed!
That was a close one...
In a different sense.
（カカシ）今のは危なかったぞ
別の意味で
（サクラ）とりゃあ～
（カカシ）あ…
ふ～
It used to be so easy.
（カカシ）昔は楽だったのになあ
I'll tear you apart!
（ナルト）ボッコボコにしてやる～！
クソ～
Damn it! You can't dodge this!
今度 足蹴り
あっ クソ～ もう！
Geez, man!
Huh?
あれっ？
Ninja don't let their opponent
get behind them over and over, you idiot!
（カカシ）忍者が何べんも
後ろ取られんな バカ
Leaf Village Secret Finger Jutsu!
（カカシ）木ノ葉隠このはがくれれ秘伝 体術奥義
あっ
（刺す音）
（ナルト）うっ
（カカシ）千年殺し！
（ナルト）うぎゃ～
A Thousand Years of Death!
She's over there, huh?
（カカシ）あそこか
（カカシ）フッ
（サクラ）サスケ君
どこにいるのかな
Sasuke-kun, where are you?
Don't tell me Sensei
already got to you!
まさか もう先生に…
No, that'd never happen to him!
いや サスケ君に限って
そんなことないわよね
（物音）
（サクラ）あっ！
（サクラ）セーフ
気づかれてない！
I'm safe! He hasn't noticed me!
Sakura, behind you.
（カカシ）サクラ 後ろ
えっ？
うわあ～！
They've been apart for two years,
（カカシ）長いこと
離れていたというのに
and yet his teamwork with Sakura
isn't that bad.
サクラとの
コンビネーションも悪くない
新刊の続きが
気になるところではあるが
Though I want to...
find out what happens next
in the new volume...
多重影分身たじゅうかげぶんしんの術！
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
As always, the sheer number
of his clones amazes me...
（カカシ）相変わらず
この数には圧倒される
（ナルト）いくぞ！
（ナルトたち）お～！
Let's go!
- Yeah!
うわあ～！
（サクラ）とや～！
Good grief... It looks like
I won't have time for reading.
（カカシ）や～れ やれ
読書してる暇は なさそうだな
おもしろくなってきたのォ
Things are getting interesting.
やりますねえ ナルト君とサクラ
Naruto-kun and Sakura
are pretty good, aren't they?
まだまだ これからだよ
Things are just getting started.
Now then, what should I do...?
（カカシ）さて どうするか
（デイダラ）フフッ
Wh-What's this strange thing?!
（砂すなの里さとの忍）おっ
なんだ この変なのは
ああっ
It's not  strange, you know.
変なのはねえだろ
（砂の里の忍）ん？ おおっ
（砂の里の忍）うう…
Sure enough, fools don't understand
what art is all about...
やっぱ バカは芸術ってもんが
分かってねえな うん
（砂の里の忍）うう…
I'll show you with your own bodies.
（デイダラ）体で教えてやるよ
True art... is an explosion!
芸術は 爆発だ！
I'm sure I heard the sound
of the bells from this way.
確かに こっちのほうから
聞こえたんだ 鈴の音
There's a possibility that
he rang them on purpose.
わざと聞かせた可能性もあるわ
Be careful.
気をつけて
Yeah, it's Kakashi-sensei, after all.
ああ カカシ先生だからな
（ナルト）ん…
（サクラ）あ…
（サスケ）うっ ああ…
Sasuke!
サスケ…
サスケ君
Sasuke-kun.
（サスケ）う… ナルト…
Naruto, Sakura... Help me.
サクラ…
助けてくれ…
I got away from Orochimaru.
大蛇丸おろちまる… ところから…
逃げてきたんだ
助けてくれ
Help me.
ナルト サクラ…
Naruto, Sakura... Please.
頼む…
It's too bad... I want to talk with Sasuke-kun
a little while longer, but...
残念だわ サスケ君とは
もうしばらく お話していたいけど
（サスケ）うっ うう…
Release!
解かい！
I'm not interested in illusions,
you see.
幻には興味ないのよね
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
影分身の術
Naruto, Kakashi-sensei's behind
that tree there.
（サクラ）ナルト
そこの木の後ろにカカシ先生
Oh, no!
（カカシ）しまった！
Yeah, I know.
ああ 分かってるってばよ！
Rasengan!
螺旋丸らせんがん！
Kakashi-sensei.
カカシ先生
Huh?
（カカシ）ん？
You have something to say, don't you?
I missed it before.
なんか言うことあるでしょ？
前は 私
聞きそびれちゃったけど
Shinobi Battle Skills, part two... Genjutsu.
（カカシ）忍戦術 その２
幻術げんじゅつ
Huh?
えっ？
What was that just now?
今の何？
Hey! Where'd Sensei go?
Huh? Huh? What's going on?
ええ？ ちょっと 先生は？
えっ？ ええ？ どうなってんの？
What's what?
ええ～ 何が何？
（サスケ）サクラ…
Sakura.
（サクラ）サスケ君？
Oh, Sasuke-kun!
S-Sakura. H-Help me.
（サスケ）サクラ…
た… 助けて… くれ…
（サクラ）あ…
うわあ～！
She fell for it so easily back then...
（カカシ）あのときは 簡単に
引っかかってくれちゃったのになあ
Kakashi-sensei,
talk about a lack of pizzazz.
カカシ先生 芸 なさすぎ
No way will we fall for the same trick
over and over again.
同じ手に 何度も
引っかかるわけないでしょ
That's right, that's right.
そうだ そうだ
（カカシ）いいや
そうともかぎらないぞ
No, that's not necessarily the case.
All right! He dropped the bells.
やりぃ！ 鈴が落ちたってばよ！
Naruto, don't.
ナルト ダメ！
（ナルト）いただき～！
They're mine...!
うわっ ああっ！
（カカシ）ほ～ら
ナルトなら 前と同じ手に…
See? Naruto would still fall
for the same trick.
ん？
Huh?
（ナルト）んなもん
引っかかるわけねえってばよ！
No way will I fall for a trap...
like this.
Wha--?!
なっ…
変わり身の術
Substitution Jutsu.
Damn it.
（ナルト）クッソ～
You idiot. Didn't I tell you?
（サクラ）バカ！
だから言ったじゃないの！
Sure enough,
the same tricks won't work, huh?
（カカシ）やっぱ
もう同じ手は通用しないか
潜入成功
Infiltration successful.
That's as far as you go.
（我愛羅があら）そこまでだ
ほう…
When I look up at the sky.
sora wo miagereba
♪～
The stars, see, are sparkling.
hoshitachi ga hora matataiteru
Each giving off its own light.
kono hoshi no hitotachi mitai ni
Like the people on this planet.
samazama na hikari wo hanatte
Yeah, so among them, I too,
sono naka de boku mo
want to shine particularly bright.
hitokiwa kagayaite itain da
I close my eyes and make a vow in my heart,
me wo tojite kokoro ni chikau
and entrust my dreams to that shooting star.
nagareboshi ni yume wo takushite
I'm in my usual park.
koko wa itsumo no kouen
I can see the night scenery on the slide.
yakei ga mieru suberidai no ue
That's been my special seat for years.
mukashi kara boku no tokutouseki
Whenever I'm worried about something, I come here.
nayami ga areba koko ni kurun desu
Just like then, I'm on my way to my dreams.
ano koro no mama yume no tochuu de
But unable to fulfil them.
ima de kanaerarezu ni irun desu
Maybe this is the end of the line.
moshikashite koko ga mou shuuten
There are days when I say weak things like that.
nante yowane wo haite shimaisou na hi mo aru
But every time, I remember.
demo sono tabi ni omoidasu
That starry sky where I looked for a shooting star.
nagareboshi wo sagashite ano hoshizora
The wish I made when I was little hasn't changed even now.
chiisana koro no negaigoto ima mukashi mo kawaranai mama
When I look up at the sky.
sora wo miagereba
The stars, see, are sparkling.
hoshitachi ga hora matataiteru
Each giving off its own light.
kono hoshi no hitotachi mitai ni
Like the people on this planet.
samazama na hikari wo hanatte
Yeah, so among them, I too,
sono naka de boku mo
want to shine particularly bright.
hitokiwa kagayaite itain da
I close my eyes and make a vow in my heart,
me wo tojite kokoro ni chikau
～♪
and entrust my dreams to that shooting star.
nagareboshi ni yume wo takushite
Next Episode
Can you see the intense smoke
from an explosion?
見えますでしょうか
ものすごい爆煙です
There's great turbulence in the skies
above the Hidden Sand.
砂隠れの里の上空で 壮絶な
乱気流が巻き起こっております
詳しく分かりますか？
Can you give us any details?
はい 風影かぜかげ様と侵入者が 空中で
激しい戦いを繰り広げているもようです
Yes. It appears Kazekage-sama
is engaged in a fierce battle in the sky
with an intruder.
住民たちは 戦いを見守るしかなく…
All the residents can do is watch... Oh!
ああ～！
Are you all right?
大丈夫ですか？
（せきばらい）
音声が途切れたようです
It seems we have lost audio.
引き続き 情報が入りしだい
お伝えします
We will continue to report the moment
we receive more information.
次回「砂の人柱力」
Next time:
"The Jinchuriki of the Sand"
The Jinchuriki of the Sand
I
n
t
e
l
i
g
e
n
c
e
R
p
o
r
t
b
y
t
h
e
A
n
b
u
B
l
a
c
k
O
p
s
Intelligence Report
by the Anbu Black Ops.
Akatsuki
“Akatsuki”.
（綱手）暁(あかつき)は みずから里を捨て
出ていった忍たちにより
The Akatsuki is
a mysterious organization
created by a group of Shinobi
who abandoned their own villages.
共通の目的を達成するため構成された
謎の組織である
This organization was created in order
to accomplish a common goal.
They wear dark clothing and robes
containing a red cloud pattern.
黒い衣 赤い雲模様の装束を身にまとい
They engage in secret activities
behind the scenes.
裏の世界で暗躍し
There is information that Orochimaru
かつては あの大蛇丸も
所属していたという情報もある
used to be affiliated
with this organization.
Until now, there are only two who
have established contact with the Leaf.
現在までに木ノ葉と接触したのは
First is Sasuke's older brother
Uchiha Itachi.
うちは一族を滅亡させた
サスケの実の兄
He possesses the Mangekyo Sharingan
万華鏡写輪眼まんげきょうしゃりんがんを持つ
うちはイタチ
Uchiha Itachi
and was the one who brought
an end to the Uchiha Clan.
The other is Kisame Hoshigaki,
そして
元 霧隠きりがくれの怪人
Kisame Hoshigaki
the former phantom of the Hidden Mist.
干柿ほしがき鬼鮫きさめの２名
During the initial contact,
even the Leaf Jonin-
第１の接触では木ノ葉が誇る上忍じょうにん
カカシ アスマ 紅くれないですら
Kakashi, Asuma and Kurenai
were no match against the pair.
They were completely defeated.
手も足も出ないという完敗を喫した
The Akatsuki's objective is to obtain
Naruto's Nine-Tailed Fox Spirit.
彼らの目的は
ナルトの九尾きゅうびを手に入れること
It remains unclear what
they intend to use it for.
その使用目的は
いまだ解明されていない
Further investigation is required.
引き続き調査を要する
T
o
b
e
c
o
n
t
i
n
u
e
d
.